Baatchia Riyadh

Fullstack Web Developer

Location: Setif, Algeria Phone: (+213) 659 46 73 28

Email: baatchia_Riyadh@protonmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/baatchia-riyadh

Portfolio: riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio GitHub: github.com/riyadh-dev

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

• Languages: TypeScript/JavaScript/NodeJS, HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, C#, WPF, XAML, WinForms

- Frameworks and libraries: ReactJS, NextJS, SolidJS, Tailwind CSS, tRPC, Zod, Prisma, drizzle-orm, Next-auth, ExpressJS, GraphQL, WebSockets, RecoilJS, Jotai, React Query, Redux Toolkit, MUI, Bootsrap, Chakra UI, .NET.
- Data Bases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Plantescale.
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Turborepo, ParcelJS, Husky, ViteJS.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- E-Commerce app: a fullstack e commerce web app with a cart system and strip checkout
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, Strip, RecoilJS, Strip...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/e-commerce-app
 - Link: e-commerce-app-self.vercel.app
- Airbnb clone: a fullstack property renting app
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, tRPC, Drizzle orm, Next-auth, MySQL(PlanetScale)...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/airbnb-clone
 - Link: airbnb-clone-riyadh-dev.vercel.app
- Social media app: a fullstack web app with instant messaging, posting, friends, likes and more
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, RecoilJS, React Query, React Router...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/social-media-app
 - Link: social-media-app-eoga.onrender.com
- Instant messaging app: a fullstack web app with instant messaging and friending system and more
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, RecoilJS, React Query, Turborepo...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/messaging-app
 - Link: messaging-app-2b7q.onrender.com
- See more: riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio/#projects

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Fluent in English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SIRIUS SERVICES Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

September 2020 – September 2022

- Developed various scripts to automate a variety of repetitive task to increase productivity and efficiency.
- Designed and develop an IEC101 Master Simulator to help company employees conduct site testing much easier.

FREELANCING Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

2019 - September 2020

• Designed and developed some simple applications for local small business

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

Masters in Computer Engineering

July 2019

- Graduated with B grading (grading is decided relative to other students).
- Developed a Full stack Web Application to facilitate the management of the Scientific Council of the institute.

ELECTRICITY AND GAS DISTRIBUTION ADMINISTRATION

Oum El Bouaghi, Algeria

INTERNSHIP

24/03/2018 – 05/04/2018

- Was responsible for daily backing up customers database.
- Was giving a basic walk-through on the IT department daily operations.

INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

License in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

July 2017

ABOUT ME

Full Stack Web developer with a master's degree in Computer Science. I have several years of experience in Web and Desktop development, focusing on frontend development (React) as well as back-End development (NodeJS). I am self-motivated person, fast learner and open to new challenges for the development of my skills.